Guide to the Dale R. Corson papers, 1935-2002.
Corson, Dale R. papers, 1963-2002.
- Series I. Correspondence
  - Letters of recommendation
    - Recommendations - Isiah C. Mathews, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 42)
    - Recommendations - Walter Nasarenko, 1980-1981 (Box 7, Folder 43)
    - Recommendations - Robert A. Plane, 1971-1974 (Box 7, Folder 44)
    - Recommendations - David and Sharon Schuman (Deep Springs), 1980-1981 (Box 7, Folder 45)
    - Recommendations - Robert Scott, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 46)
    - Recommendations - Margaret G. Sommers, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 47)
    - Recommendations - Thomas L. Tobin, 1974-1976 (Box 7, Folder 48)
    - Recommendations - John D. Wilson, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 49)
- Series II. Articles and speeches
  - List of Speeches, 1959-1988 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Articles and Speeches; General Correspondence, 1959-1973 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Comments to Speeches (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Meetings/Agendas (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - List of Articles and Speeches, 1957-1977 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Electromagnetic Induction in Moving Systems, Mar. 1956 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Notes - Remarks to Engineering Freshmen, 1959-1960 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Notes - Talk to Freshman C.E.'s and E.E.'s; Future Technical Problems, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Notes for Remarks at Triangle Initiation, Jan. 16, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Notes for Remarks to A.A.V.W., Jan. 20, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Notes for Remarks at Tau Beta Pi, May 24, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Letter to Freshman - Cornell Engineer, July 29, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Article - Science or Engineering?, Sept. 23, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Speech at Bard Dinner, Sept. 24, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Notes for Remarks at Faculty Meeting, Oct. 12, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Notes for Remarks to Secondary School Headmasters, Oct. 14, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Speech at Hollister Hall Dedication, Oct. 16, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Speech to Cornell University Council, Oct. 17, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Notes for Remarks at Faculty Meetings, Nov. 9, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Notes for Remarks to Mechanical Engineering 5th Year Students, Nov. 13, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Notes for Remarks to A.S.M.E., Nov. 23, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Notes for Remarks at Chi Epsilon, Jan. 10, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Book Review - The Neutron Story, Jan. 20, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Notes for Remarks to E.E. 5th Year Students, Jan. 24, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Notes for Remarks at Western Electric in Indianapolis, Feb. 25, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Notes for Remarks to Cornell Society of Engineers in Boston, Apr. 27, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Remarks - Cleveland and NYC Cornell Club and Society of Engineers, May 2, 12, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Notes for Remarks to Student Prof. Groups, May 5, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Paper - The Next Ten to Twenty Years in Engineering at C.U., June 1960 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Notes for Remarks at Sloan Fnd. Mtg. in Hot Springs, VA., July 14, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Speech - Extra High Voltage Dedication, Sept. 14, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Speech to Freshmen, Sept. 17, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Notes - ECPD - Montreal, Canada, Oct. 4, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Notes for Remarks at Faculty Meeting, Oct. 10, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Notes for Remarks to Secondary School Headmasters, Oct. 12, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Notes for Remarks - CURW, Oct. 26, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Notes for Remarks to M.E. and E.E. Seniors, Nov. 18, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Notes for Remarks at Faculty Meeting, Dec. 12, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Notes for Remarks to N.Y. Cornell Society, 1961? (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - Notes for Remarks at Electrical Engineering Faculty Meeting (Morale), Feb. 5, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - Notes for Remarks to Engineering Club, Sidney, NY, Feb. 21, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 41)
  - Speech - Reactor Dedication (Published Version), Feb. 23, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - Notes for Remarks to Essex County Counselors, Mar. 2, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 43)
  - Notes for Remarks at Acacia, Apr. 4, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 44)
  - Notes for Remarks at American Ceramic Society, Rochester, NY, Apr. 7, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 45)
  - Letter to Cornell Society of Engineers, July 1961 (Box 8, Folder 46)
  - Letter of Welcome to Freshmen Engineers - Cornell Engineer, July 20, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 47)
  - Research Versus Undergraduate Education, Oct. 1961 (Box 8, Folder 48)
  - Remarks - Graduate Engineering Ed. - At ASEE Meeting, Potsdam, NY, Oct. 4, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 49)
  - Notes for Remarks to M.E.'s and E.E.'s, Nov. 17, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 50)
  - Speech - Cornell Reactor Dedication, Jan. 9, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 51)
  - Notes for Remarks at Cornell Fund Meeting in NYC, Jan. 13, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 52)
  - Notes - Graduate Committee, Jan. 18, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 53)
  - Some Major Technical Problems of the Next 25 Years, Feb. 1962 (Box 8, Folder 54)
  - Notes for Remarks to Secondary School Counselors in Detroit, Mar. 16, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 55)
  - Remarks to Alumni in Detroit, Mar. 17, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 56)
  - Notes - I&LR Seminar on R&D, Mar. 18, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 57)
  - Notes for Remarks to Cornell Club of New York, Mar. 28, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 58)
  - Notes for Remarks to Cornell Society of Engineers in Philadelphia, Boston, and New York, Apr. 1962 (Box 8, Folder 59)
  - Notes for Remarks at Engineering Day, May 5, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 60)
  - Notes - EPM, May 24, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 61)
  - Letter to Alumni, July 11, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 62)
  - Notes for Remarks to Freshmen, Sept. 15, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 63)
  - New Dimensions in Engineering, Oct. 1962 (Box 8, Folder 64)
  - Paper - Laboring Instruction in Engineering Education, Oct. 1, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 65)
  - Article - Letter to Cornell Soc. of Engineers, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 66)
  - Article - The C-14 Method of Historical Dating, Jan. 1963 (Box 8, Folder 67)
  - Notes - EPM, Jan. 17, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 68)
  - Paper - Study of Engineering Laboratory Education, Feb. 1963 (Box 8, Folder 69)
  - Notes - Remarks at Evanston Township High School to Counselors and Teachers, Feb. 14, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 70)
  - Problems of Graduate Education and Research, May 30, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 71)
  - Notes, Remarks in NY; Notes - Remarks in Boston, Apr. 4, 10, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 72)
  - Notes for Remarks at Phi Eta Sigma (Freshman Honorary), Apr. 25, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 73)
  - Notes - College Teaching Seminar, May 20, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 74)
  - Notes for Remarks at Foreign Student Dinner, Nov. 6, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 75)
  - Speech - J.P. Inauguration, Sept. 9, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 76)
  - Speech - Bard Dedication, Oct. 5, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 77)
  - Speech - Cornell Council, Oct. 5, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 78)
  - Speech - Arecibo Dedication, Oct. 31-Nov. 1, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 79)
  - Speech - Continuing Education Conference, Columbia University, Nov. 8, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 80)
  - Speech - Cornell National Scholars, Dec. 9, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 81)
  - Speech - On History, Problems, Changes, and Future of Cornell, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 82)
  - Speech - Introduction of Professor Feynman, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 83)
  - Article - 1964 Cornellian, Jan. 9, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 84)
  - Speech - Multiversity or Liberal Arts, Jan. 11, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 85)
  - Speech - Pi Tau Sigma Initiation Banquet, Jan. 19. 1964 (Box 8, Folder 86)
  - Speech - Saturday Night Club, Jan. 25, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 87)
  - Speech - Cornell Women's Club, Feb. 15, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 88)
  - Speech - Current Trends in University Organization, Programs, and Policies, Feb. 21, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 89)
  - Speech - To Trustees "Budget Planning", Apr. 17, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 90)
  - Speech - New York State Regents, May 21, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 91)
  - Speech - Problems of an Expanding Population in Our Modern Technological Society, June 18, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 92)
  - Speech - To Highway Supts. and Town Clerics, June 30, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 93)
  - Speech - Opening Remarks for R.F. Kennedy Rally, Sept. 28, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 94)
  - Speech - Ag. Business Council, Syracuse, NY, Oct. 28, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 95)
  - Notes - Special Faculty Meeting, Dec. 4, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 96)
  - Notes - To Trustees on CU Growth, Jan. 1965 (Box 8, Folder 97)
  - Speech - On Transportation, Mar. 20, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 98)
  - Speech - Parents' Day, Apr. 24, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 99)
  - Speech - Student Government Installation, Apr. 28, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 100)
  - Speech - Cornell Club of Rochester, May 11, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 101)
  - Article - Introduction to Philip Sporn's "Vistas in Electric Power", July 7, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 102)
  - Speech - Alumni Annual Giving, Sept. 26, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 103)
  - Speech - Dedication of Bioclimatic Laboratories, Oct. 26, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 104)
  - Speech - The Role of the University in New York Agriculture (Soil Fert. Conf.), Jan. 12, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 105)
  - Article - Toward Education for the Engineering Profession, Mar. 1966 (Box 8, Folder 106)
  - Speech - The University Budget, Mar. 1966 (Box 8, Folder 107)
  - Speech - To Saturday Night Club - (CRE: Education in Iron Curtain Countries), Mar. 19, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 108)
  - Speech - Administrator's Briefing, Sept. 30, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 109)
  - Letter to Robert Braden - Alumni News, Feb. 1966 (Box 8, Folder 110)
  - Speech - Cornell Fund, Oct. 1, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 111)
  - Article - Tribute to Alan Holmberg, Oct. 19, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 112)
  - Speech - The Role of the University in Technological Advance, Oct. 21, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 113)
  - Article - Tribute to Professor Peter J.W. Debye, Nov. 17, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 114)
  - Speech - Cornell Fund, NY, Jan. 5, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 115)
  - Speech - N.I.C.B., Jan. 18, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 116)
  - Notes - Trojan Horse Incident, Jan. 20, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 117)
  - Speech - The Importance of Being Non-Professional, Apr. 1967 (Box 8, Folder 118)
  - Speech - Caplan Dinner, May 15, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 119)
  - Memorandum to Trustees re Cutting Express, Mar. 7, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 120)
  - Speech - Class 1930, Mar. 19, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 121)
  - Speech - Engineering College Council, Apr. 12, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 122)
  - Speech - Trustees Dinner at Lab. of Ornithology, Apr. 18, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 123)
  - Speech - Mohawk Valley Community College Commencement, May 26, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 124)
  - Speech - Federation of Cornell Men's Club, Oct. 25, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 125)
  - Speech - College of Ag. Council, Oct. 28, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 126)
  - Speech - Introduction pf President Romulo, Nov. 18, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 127)
  - Letter in Reply to Tewksbury Letter on the Role of CU - Alumni News, Jan. 3, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 128)
  - Letter - To Board of Trustees - Report on the Budget, Jan. 7, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 129)
  - Speech - AAPT Panel, Feb. 3, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 130)
  - Speech - "Communication from the Provost to the University Faculty", Mar. 12, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 131)
  - Speech - "The Problem from Two Points of View: Dean and Provost" - 6th Institute for Engineering Deans, Mar. 24, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 132)
  - Article - "When is a Deficit Not a Deficit?", Apr. 10, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 133)
  - Speech at Tau Beta Pi Dinner, Apr. 17, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 134)
  - Speech - Barton Hal Assembly, Apr. 26, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 135)
  - Speech - Dean Deitrick Retirement Dinner, May 27, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 136)
  - Speech - Parents Convocation, Sept. 10, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 137)
  - Speech - Freshman Convocation, Sept. 10, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 138)
  - Speech - Constituent Assembly 2pm, Sept. 14, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 139)
  - Speech - Faculty Meeting, Sept. 24, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 140)
  - Article - "Perkins the Man and Perkins the President" (Alumni News), June 9, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 141)
  - Statement before the NYS Senate Finance Subcommittee on the Ombudsman, Oct. 9, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 142)
  - Speech - Fed. of Men's and Women's Clubs, Oct. 10, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 143)
  - Speech - Welcome to Alumni, Oct. 11, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 144)
  - Speech - Vietnam Mobilization Rally, Oct. 15, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 145)
  - Speech - "State of the Univ." before Trustees and Council, Oct. 17, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 146)
  - Speech - Los Angeles Alumni, Oct. 30, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 147)
  - Speech - Ithaca Common Council, Nov. 5, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 148)
  - Speech - Faculty Council, Nov. 14, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 149)
  - Article - Letter to Tuller - Alumni News, Jan. 6, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 150)
  - Speech - Class Officers, NY, Jan. 17, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 151)
  - Speech - State of the University Report to Trustees, Jan. 23, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 152)
  - Speech - To Univ. Faculty, Feb. 11, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 153)
  - Speech - To Orlando and Palm Beach Alumni, Feb. 19-20, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 154)
  - Speech to Graduate Faculty regarding Black Grad. Students, Feb. 27, 197- (Box 8, Folder 155)
  - Speech to University Faculty regarding University Financial Situation, Mar. 11, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 156)
  - Speech to University Faculty regarding Increase in Black Grad. Student Admissions, Mar. 11, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 157)
  - Speech - Rotary Club, Mar. 25, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 158)
  - Speech - Introduction of Arthur Goldberg, Mar. 25, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 159)
  - Speech to Faculty about African Fire, Apr. 3, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 160)
  - Speech - Cornell Convocation (New York), Apr. 18, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 161)
  - Speech - To Faculty (re: Attacks on Universities, Cambodia, etc.), May 6, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 162)
  - Speech - ROTC Statement to Faculty, May 13, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 163)
  - Speech - Inaugural (Commencement), June 8, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 164)
  - Speech by Dr. J.A. Stratton, June 8, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 165)
  - Speech - Class of 1920, June 12, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 166)
  - Statement - Jean Perkins Memorial Service, June 26, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 167)
  - Speech - To Parents (Convocation), Sept. 9, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 168)
  - Speech - To Freshmen (Convocation), Sept. 10, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 169)
  - Panel Discussion - WVBR Newsbeat, Sept. 18, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 170)
  - Speech - To University Faculty, Sept. 23, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 171)
  - Speech (Remarks) - Memorial Service for T.P. Wright, Sept. 26, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 172)
  - Speech - Boston Alumni, Oct. 17, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 173)
  - Speech - To Board of Trustees and Cornell Council, Oct. 23, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 174)
  - Speech - Princeton Alumni, Nov. 20, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 175)
  - Speech - Library Associates Group, Dec. 1, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 176)
  - Article - Foreward for T.P. Wright's Book, Dec. 22, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 177)
  - Speech - Cooperative Extension Club, Jan. 4, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 178)
  - Speech - To University Senate on Access to the Campus Report, Jan. 7, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 179)
  - Article - Report to Trustees on Budget Plan and Budget for 1971-1972, Jan. 13, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 180)
  - Speech to University Faculty on Access Report and S. African Incident, Jan. 13, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 181)
  - Speech - Miami Alumni, Feb. 22, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 182)
  - Speech - Buffalo Alumni, Mar. 20, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 183)
  - Speech - Albany Alumni, Mar. 22, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 184)
  - Speech - Faculty Council of Representatives, Mar. 24, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 185)
  - Speech - Rotary Club, Mar. 24, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 186)
  - Speech - Development Advisory Committee Meeting, Apr. 16, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 187)
  - Speech - Pittsburgh Alumni, Apr. 23, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 188)
  - Remarks - Introduction of Senator Hartke, May 5, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 189)
  - Speech - Tower Club, Pierre Hotel, NYC, May 11, 19171 (Box 8, Folder 190)
  - Speech - College of Emporia Alumni Reunion, May 21, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 191)
  - Speech - Johnson Testimonial Dinner, May 25, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 192)
  - Speech - Commencement, June 7, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 193)
  - Speech - Class of 1921, June 11, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 194)
  - Speech - Alumni Reunion, June 12, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 195)
  - Student-Parent Convention, Aug. 30, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 196)
  - Speech - University Faculty Meeting, Sept. 23, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 197)
  - Article - The Crisis in Higher Education, Oct. 12, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 198)
  - Speech - Joint Session Cornell Council and Trustees, Oct. 16, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Speech - Boston Alumni, Oct. 19, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Speech - Engineering Convocation, Oct. 22, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Report - President's Animal Report, Oct. 29, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Speech - Noyes Testimonial Dinner, Nov. 1, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Crisis in Higher Education, Nov. 8, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Speech - San Francisco Alumni, Nov. 12, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Discussion - With A&S Faculty, Dec. 9, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Speech - State of the University to Trustees, Jan. 20, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Speech - Cornell Class Officers, Jan. 22, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Speech - Washington Higher Education Group, Feb. 8, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Speech - Naples/Sarasota Alumni, Feb. 15, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Speech - State of the University to Trustees, Mar. 18, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Remarks - Memorial Service for Henri Sack, Mar. 19, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Speech - Syracuse Alumni, Cincinnati Alumni, Mar. 27, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Speech - Rebmann Testimonial Dinner, Apr. 4, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Welcoming Remarks - Native American Association Conference, Apr. 4, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Joint Personal Statement by Ivy League Presidents, Apr. 14, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Paper - Presented to University of Arizona Foundation, Apr. 28, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Speech - Nassau County Alumni, May 5, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Speech - Tower Club, May 10, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Speech - Commencement 1972, May 26, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Speech - Class of 1922 Dinner, June 9, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Speech - To Alumni at Reunion, June 10, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Speech - Class of 1917 Dinner, June 10, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Speech - Parent's Convocation, Aug 8, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Speech - Student's Convocation, Aug. 31, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Statement - At Munich Tragedy at Olympics, Sept. 6, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Speech - University Faculty Meeting, Sept. 15, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Letter from W.D. Cook to Dr. Corson, Sept. 22, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Speech - University Senate Meeting, Oct. 10, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Speech - Dedication of Uris Building, Oct. 13, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Speech - Cornell Council - Board of Trustees Meeting, Oct. 13, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Speech - Engineering Council Dinner Honoring Dean Schultz, Oct. 20, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Speech - 50th Anniversary Hotel School Banquet Honoring Dean Beck, Oct. 24, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Discussion - With Education Class 581 Class on Student Personnel Administration, Oct. 26, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Speech - Dedication of Class of 1922 Hall, Oct. 28, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Speech - Los Angeles Alumni, Nov. 30, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - Article - Friendly, Generous Bankers and Interest Rates, Jan. 11, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - Speech - State of the University to Board of Trustees, Jan. 26, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - Article - Prudent Unrestricted Investment Income Distribution, Feb. 11, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - Speech - For Florida Alumni Dinners, Feb. 16, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 42)
  - Springfield-Hartford Alumni Dinner, Mar. 9, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 43)
  - Prudent Unrestricted Investment Income Distribution, Mar. 11, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 44)
  - Article - The President Views Athletics, Mar. 14, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 45)
  - Speech - Cornell and the New Educational Realities, Rochester Alumni, Mar. 31, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 46)
  - Paper - University Long Range Plan - Intro/Memo to Trustees, Apr. 1973 (Box 9, Folder 47)
  - Speech - Cornell University Senate (4th Session), Apr. 3, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 48)
  - Letter - To Parents, Apr. 17, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 49)
  - Graduate Education and Research: A Strategy for the 1970's, Apr. 24, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 50)
  - Speech (paper) - Graduate Education and Research for the 1970's, given at AAV Meeting, Apr. 24, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 51)
  - Speech - Buffalo Alumni Honoring Saperson and Newbury, May 2, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 52)
  - Statement - President's Statement on Financial Matters, May 2, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 53)
  - Speech - Westchester County Alumni, May 12, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 54)
  - Speech - Law School Convocation, May 19, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 55)
  - Speech - Parratt Retirement Dinner, May 21, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 56)
  - Speech - Commencement, May 25, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 57)
  - Speech - Newman Meadow Dedication, June 7, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 58)
  - Speech - Class of 1923 Dinner, June 7, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 59)
  - Article - Confessions of an Amateur Eclipse Chaser (Alumni News), July 17, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 60)
  - Speech - Parent's Convocation, Aug. 29, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 61)
  - Speech - Labor College Commencement, Sept. 3, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 62)
  - Speech - Senate Meeting, Sept. 11, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 63)
  - Speech - Faculty Meeting, Sept. 12, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 64)
  - Speech - "Universities - Where Do We Go from Here?" Trustee Council Weekend Panel Introduction, Oct. 19, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 65)
  - Speech - Denver Alumni, Nov. 12, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 66)
  - Speech - Circle Meeting "Where Are We Headed?", Nov. 19, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 67)
  - Statement - Death of Morris Bishop, Nov. 21, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 68)
  - Speech - Arts and Sciences Faculty Meeting, Dec. 4, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 69)
  - Speech - Cornell Club of Washington, Feb. 7, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 70)
  - University Faculty, May 15, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 71)
  - Honoring Judge Tuttle in Atlanta, Feb. 14, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 72)
  - Speech - University Faculty, Feb. 20, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 73)
  - Draft of Article - The Arithmetic of Tenure, Feb. 22, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 74)
  - Statement - Before Costigian Committee, Feb. 26, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 75)
  - Untitled, Feb. 27, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 76)
  - Speech - State of the University Board of Trustees Meeting, Mar. 15, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 77)
  - Article - The Arithmetic of Tenure, Mar. 2, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 78)
  - Speech - University Senate, Apr. 2, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 79)
  - Gates Lectures, given by Bob Morrison: I. Making the Man, II. Making the Career, III. The Lesson for Us, Apr. 22, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 80)
  - Background Papers for Meetings with Faculty, May 1974 (Box 9, Folder 81)
  - Speech - Dinner Honoring John Spencer Olin, May 1, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 82)
  - Speech - MacKesey Retirement Dinner, May 4, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 83)
  - Speech - Alpha Delta Phi Reception, May 7, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 84)
  - Speech - Testimonial Dinner for Charles Treman, May 15, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 85)
  - Speech - Testimonial Dinner for Kenneth Turk, May 16, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 86)
  - Speech - Tower Club Dinner, May 23, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 87)
  - Speech - Cornell Law School Convocation, May 25, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 88)
  - Speech - Anecdotal Material - Dinner for Retiring Deans, May 28, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 89)
  - Speech - Medical College Commencement, May 29, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 90)
  - Speech - Dedication of Spencer T. Olin Chemistry Lab, June 2, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 91)
  - Speech - Dinner Honoring Dedication of Olin Chemistry Lab, June 2, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 92)
  - Speech - ROTC Commissioning Ceremony, June 3, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 93)
  - Speech - Commencement, June 3, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 94)
  - Speech - Testimonial Dinner for Dean Poppensiek, June 7, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 95)
  - Speech - 50 Year Class Reunion Dinner, June 14, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 96)
  - Speech - Annual Report to Cornell Alumni Association, June 15, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 97)